goal plunging is one of my favorite ways
to recover my sore muscles but the
problem with a lot of them is that they
take up a lot of space and they aren't
portable now that is not the case with
the energized cold punch tub this
inflatable plunge only takes about 15
minutes for you to set up it filters
your water so you're not having to drain
it after every single use you can
control the chiller with your phone but
the cherry on top you can deflate it and
put it in the included duffel bag and
take it on the road with you so one of
my favorite coal plunges on the market
right now so let's dive into this full
review
[Music]
what's up y'all it's Jake back at the
barbin garage gym obviously we're
outside today and that's because we got
another cold plunge video for you this
time we're going to be talking about the
energized cold plunge tub now you all
know how this whole process works in
this video today I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about this
cold plunge from the price some of my
pros and cons I've experienced you might
experience as well most importantly who
should or maybe should not purchase one
of these now hold on real fast before I
start doing all that I gotta let you
know we've reviewed a ton I'm talking a
ton of cold plunges on barbin.com we did
the hard part for you went ahead and
compiled a best list of all of our
favorite options on the market so if you
want to check that out all you gotta do
is search bar Bend best cold punches
that list is going to pull right up for
you and you can find out for yourself
which ones we like the best
foreign
things about this cold plunge and we got
to talk about the installation process
all right so everything said and done it
only takes around 15 to 20 minutes and I
timed myself and it took me about six
minutes to inflate the actual tub and
the cover itself right here so
everything else is only 10 12 minutes or
so that's that's a really nice thing
right there for obvious reasons if you
want to take it down you know you
definitely can I love how there's a
filter connected to the chiller right
here it's going to obviously filter your
water for you and prevent you from you
know having to drain the water after
every use or even every other use plus
you're going to get a four month water
maintenance kit that way you know
everything's nice and sanitary and
another awesome selling point with this
plunge is the portability it's one of
our favorite portable options on the
market super easy to do you know only
takes around five minutes or so to
deflate it and then you can Fold It Up
Put it and that included a duffel bag
and easily take it on the road with you
now you are going to have to you know
bring that Chiller with you unless you
don't want to actually notice that
there's some Stoppers that are already
attached to where you up the hose I'll
show you guys all that just a little bit
you can actually use ice with this if
you want you know if you don't want to
bring the chiller with you you still
have access to a hose you can plug it up
fill it up with water and then you know
toss in your ice and you're good to go
now there's still a few things you need
to know and first of all we got to talk
about the money you're going to be
spending around five grand on this cold
plunge right here now while I ultimately
think you know the portability and the
option to you know take it down and
store it you know whenever you want is
you know pretty much worthy of that
price tag you can still go and get an
acrylic one for around the same amount
of money and you know sticking with that
acrylic you know while I I think this
build right here is fine you know they
use the same drop stitch polyester
fabric that's used with inflatable
kayaks and paddle boards but it still
probably isn't going to be as durable as
an acrylic you know tub now those
acrylic models you know they literally
resemble a bathtub so they're going to
be bigger than this model right here but
this still isn't necessarily small I
guess you could say compared to like you
know like the ones that resemble a
barrel also we need to talk about the
condensation so I'm sure you can see it
right now this is not water leaking this
is literally just some condensation from
being outside it's going to happen it's
part of it I don't wouldn't necessarily
you know say it's a negative of aspects
or something that you definitely need to
remember and then also we need to talk
about the fact that you're going to have
to you know refill this with air every
so often so they claim on the website
you know it really is only going to
release one to two PSI per month but I
didn't necessarily find that to be true
I've had to you know pump more air into
this bad point after just a couple of
days so you know all these things just
keep all those in mind whenever you're
going to make this purchase
so the energized cold plunge tub is
going to run you right around five
thousand dollars as I mentioned just a
second ago and honestly I'm kind of torn
at the end of the day on whether or not
this is you know a good price because
yes the portability is really nice the
option to take it down and store it
whenever you need to or want to is
really the main selling point but you
know if you're wanting a you know a
plunge to be stationary at all times you
can get an acrylic one as I mentioned
for around the same amount of money and
that's going to be more durable and be
able to withstand you know the harsh
elements of being outdoors probably
better than this one will right here now
compared to you know the barrels that
you have to use a lot of water and a lot
of ice that don't come with a chiller
yes this is double the price but you're
also going to be you're not going to be
wasting as much water ice and plastic
and everything like that so it's going
to save you money in the long run
compared to those other models because
of the chiller and the filter and all
that good stuff
foreign
so once again the energized cold plunge
tub is made from a drop stitch polyester
fabric which is you know the equivalent
of you know inflatable kayaks and paddle
boards the 1800 watt Chiller requires a
120 volt Outlet which is once again
standard at home and it's going to drop
the water temperature from 65 degrees to
37 degrees and around four to five hours
which is you know pretty solid to be
honest now that Chiller does contain a
micron filter it's recommended you
replace it once a month and then
sanitize your water weekly which once
again you do get that four month supply
of the sanitation kit which is honestly
a really nice touch most companies
aren't including that with your purchase
so I just personally really like that
the included cover is really nice you
know you have you know a lock on it
right here it's you know that's nice if
you have you know kids and you don't
want them to get in it you can keep this
locked there's actually a code right
here which is really nice too they can't
get in it it's just a nice safety
feature plus you know the main point
here is that it's going to help keep
those water temperatures locked in
whether you know you're 37 degrees or or
you're testing out that 107 degree water
that's gonna be really nice for you kind
of work in tandem with that Chiller
there's a hose hookup it's really nice
you know you used to attach it to one of
the outlets on the back I'll show you
guys in a little bit that way you know
you can drain all your water away from
your electrical electrical components
excuse me and all that all that stuff
right there and then lastly it weighs 25
pounds on its own so you know once you
deflate it it's really easy for you to
stash it in that duffel bag and take it
on the road with you as I've mentioned a
couple times but it's going to weigh
around 600 to 700 pounds when it's full
of water so if you're placing it on a
deck that deck's probably you know
assuming it's going to be strong enough
to you know handle that but that's
definitely just something that you want
to keep in mind
all right so I just want to highlight a
few things look close for y'all and I
want to talk about the accessories and
everything that kind of comes with your
purchase but first of all your Chiller
is going to come in this box right here
and they actually recommend you keep it
for whatever you know travel purposes
and it goes in there and there's wood in
here and the styrofoam is going to help
you know protect it now as you can see
there's a bunch of stuff in here just to
you know consolidate here I just decided
to leave everything that orange tube
right there this is your repair kit you
got your skimming net obviously your
Water Sanitation and your testing strips
which is all really nice now this is
going to be your pump as you can see you
know it's pretty much a classic looks
like a bicycle pump right so all you got
to do you just take this end right here
and there's a little opening up here and
on on the actual sponge at the bottom
right here you just you know screw this
in
Pump It Up there's actually a deflate
and inflate side right here and it's
really nice make sure you check out
which one you don't want to be doing one
thing anyways you also have a pressure
gauge right here on the top you know
it's actually recommended you do not
fill this over 10 psi so it's nice that
you know this has that it's really handy
right so
let's talk about the actual Chiller
first now I don't know if you can hear
it or not it does make a little bit of
noise but it's relatively not that bad
all right so this is obviously your
power button right here this next button
right here will actually change from
Fahrenheit to Celsius if you wanted to
now this s is stands for set all right
so all you got to do is press the S and
then you use these arrows over here on
the right you can see on the bottom
that's the intended temperature so it's
really easy set it whatever you want
we're at 38 right now it's cooling we're
trying to get it to 37 press set again
and it's going to lock in and that W
right there is for Wi-Fi so relatively
straightforward right there you do have
a set of wheels right here and the
filter is on the back it's going to
filter your water I think it's seven
times every hour which is a really nice
thing now
this is your host hookup this is going
to go in right on this water Outlet
right here and that's pretty
self-explanatory you just screw it in
you know Screw on the hose and then
you're able to direct all that water
away from all of your electrical stuff
and you don't want to get electrocuted
right now this is what I was talking
about these little Stoppers so whenever
you actually unbox this plunge there's
gonna be one of these attached here
sorry about the dogs it's gonna be more
attached here and over here now that's
gonna be really nice you know say you
don't have the option to use the chiller
you can always use ice if you want now
when it comes to the actual you know
materials remember this is a drop stitch
polyester fabric right here
once again it's identical to the
inflatable kayaks and paddle boards so
you know pretty solid I can put a body
weight on it it's not going to collapse
or anything like that which is obviously
what you want now as you can see it's on
zero zero right here on these clips
that's you know unlocked if you put it
on even if you just put one of them on
it's not going to unlock so that's
really nice you know safety feature
right there and actually something I
forgot to mention was there's actually a
lock button as well with the chiller
that way you can lock that temperature
in nobody can mess with it or anything
like that now
I think you know what time it is
it's time for the fun part I'm gonna hop
in here you know we're sitting at 38
degrees right now that definitely gets
the job done just give me one second and
we're gonna hop in here
as you can see I don't know if you
actually I don't know if you can tell or
not there's ripples you know that's
where that water is coming in and at the
bottom that's where that water is
getting sucked into the tubings back
here and that water is getting filtered
all right so that's just really nice
right there
oh
here we go
all right takes a few seconds
get your breath as I said you know we're
at 38 degrees
that's really really cold
body kind of goes numb after a few
seconds like that so I'm good to go now
and it's about 30 inches deep so tall I
guess you could say so definitely able
to you know completely duck under like I
just did you know even if you're over
six feet tall this is probably still
going to work for you which is really
nice man this is cold and you can
absolutely get all the way under
whenever you want I'm not trying to
completely freeze myself out right now
as I do this video so I'm not going to
go shoulder deep but you definitely can
if you want to remember when it comes to
cold plunging you really
I wouldn't say more than seven minutes
and you could go to 10 minutes if you
want to but seven should probably be the
tops just because after that you're
really not getting that much more of an
effect on your body so definitely keep
that in mind yeah overall this is really
nice I can easily you know lean up
against it put my arms on it I'm putting
all my body weight right here on my arms
right now and it's holding me up so
definitely strong enough sturdy enough
to really get the job done for pretty
much everybody
thank you
all right so let's take a second and
talk about you know who this you know
cold plunge is intended for or maybe you
know not so much so you know if you're
wanting a highly portable cold plunge
you know one that you can take down and
put in storage this is one of the best
options that are on the market super
easy to do that you know it only takes a
few minutes to deflate it and put it in
a duffel bag it's a really nice touch
and also you know if you don't want to
be super wasteful with water and ice and
you know the plastic that comes with the
ice and all of that that filtration
system right here is going to be a
really nice touch for you
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase this cold plunge really
money you know is obviously a factor
it's five grand and if you're not crazy
about the material you can find you know
an acrylic one as I mentioned for the
same exact price so you know you
definitely want to remember that space
is obviously still a factory you know
this is still smaller than you know
those bigger acrylic tubs but it's still
you know five feet long and three feet
wide or so you obviously need to make
sure you have enough space just to store
it at home and then one thing that I
forgot to mention earlier is that you
know if you live somewhere where the you
know temperatures are getting sub 40
degrees actually I think on their
website it says 37 degrees if it's below
that actually really do on the risk of
you know the tubes right here freezing
that water freezing and kind of
everything getting messed up so during
those cold winter months this really
isn't going to be the best option for
you so definitely just keep all those
things in mind
all right
[Music]
all right that's a wrap on today's
review over the energized cold plunge
tub yes this is you know pretty pricey
for some people but you know at the end
of the day you know this is you know one
of my favorite cool punches on the
market it's definitely my favorite
portable cold plunge on the market right
now it's really easy to set it up only
takes around 15 minutes or so you can
use it with or without the chiller if
you really want to thanks for watching
y'all hope this video was really helpful
and I was able to answer any questions
you have about this cold plunge you know
the drill keep your eyes out for my next
video for now head over to barbin.com so
we have a full written review about this
product all you got to do is search bar
Bend energize cold plunge review it's
gonna pull right up for you you can read
over everything we talked about here
today you might even learn something new
I'll catch y'all next time
thank you
[Music]